翻译：allenlovestar
翻译：gkall
翻译：wyk8818
校对：彼岸荼蘼
时间轴：wxw996
时间轴：凭陵新月
后期：Sung1219
故事发生在德克萨斯州
露丝
Ruth.
等等啊  露丝
Hey, Ruth.
-你上哪儿去  -回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
-家不在这边  -不回我家
- Home's the other way. - Not mine.
你要回娘家啊
Are you going back to your mom's?
那得走15英里路
It's a 15-mile walk.
我知道
I know how far it is.
好吧  我跟你一起走
All right. Well, then, I'll just walk with you.
你爱干啥干啥
You do whatever you want.
我想带你回我们家
What I want to do is take you back to our house.
你为什么和弗雷迪说你要自己动手
Why did you tell Freddy you were gonna strike out on your own?
我不记得说过这话啊  不过真要说了
I don't think I said that, but if I did,
我说的"自己"也是指我们俩
when I say, "On my own," I mean you and me.
一直都是咱俩
I always mean you and me.
你是要甩了我吗
You gonna leave me?
没有啊  我不会甩你
No, I'm not gonna leave you.
没人要甩你
Nobody's leaving any...
老娘会先甩了你
'Cause I will leave you first.
有意思吗
It's not... funny.
我不会离开你的
I'm not gonna leave you.
你也一样离不开我
You're not gonna leave me.
如果你真走了  我就跟着你
Because if you do, I'll just follow you.
我不想去坐牢
I don't want to go to jail.
不会坐牢的
Not going to jail.
你那破地方根本不算是个家
And that shack ain't a home.
我在想办法啊
Well, I'm working on it.
我觉得自己怀孕了
And I think I'm gonna have a baby.
我们要有小孩了吗
We're gonna have a baby?
你没抓狂吗
You're not mad?
没有啊
I'm not mad.
我妈会帮忙养着的
No, my mama will raise it.
我能偷个吻吗
Can I steal a kiss?
别闹了  怪痒痒的
Stop it. That tickles.
对胎儿不是应该唱唱歌什么的吗
That's what you're supposed to do, is sing songs.
就说说话吧
Just talk.
你累吗
Are you tired?
好了
All right.
我不会有事的
I'll be fine.
我去去就回
I'll be back in five minutes.
我们正在追捕嫌疑人
We've got a little bit of a chase on our hands here...
我跟你说  走进去
I tell you, walking into there,
你会觉得自己要去见魔鬼
you feel like you're meeting the devil.
所有警车请准备支援
All cars for backup.
重复一遍  所有警车  所有警车
I repeat, all cars, all cars...
-所有警车  -该死  服务员买单
- any and all cars. - Shit. All right. Check, hon.
我中弹了
I'm hit!
我打着人了
I shot someone.
我好像打中了谁
I think I shot someone.
没事的
It's okay.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-我打着人了  -糟糕了
- I think I shot someone. - Oh, shit.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
枪给我  露丝
Give me the gun, Ruth.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
听我说
Listen to me.
我们站起来  走出去
We're gonna stand up and walk out there.
-不好  -我先走
- No. - Okay. I'm gonna go first.
你跟着我  这事儿就这样了
You come after me. That's how it's gonna be.
不  我们能脱身的
No. We can make it.
我们跑的话或许能逃掉
We can make it if we run.
-我们跑不掉的  -能行的
- We can't make it, Ruth. - Yeah, we can.
他们会开枪打死我们的
They're gonna shoot us.
如果我们待在这里
If we stay in here,
他们会当场打死我们的
they're gonna shoot us right where we are.
不要  求你了
No. Please.
我必须这么做
I'm gonna do it.
我不要  我不要坐牢
I'm not gonna do it. I'm not going to jail!
你跟他们说一切都是我干的
You got to tell them I did everything.
把所有事情推到我和弗雷迪身上
Tell them that me and Freddy did everything.
是我把枪放在你手里的
You got a gun in your hands 'cause I put it there.
告诉他们你吓坏了
You tell them you were scared
于是我把枪给你了
and I put it there.
我坐不了几年牢的
I'm gonna be out in a blink,
我很快就回来
and I'm gonna come back.
你等着我就行
All you got to do is wait for me.
我发誓我会回来找你的
I promise I'll come get you.
乖乖等我  好吗
Just wait for me, okay?
等我
Just wait for me.
我儿子死了
So, I lost my boy.
现在只剩下你和鲍勃
And that leaves you and Bob.
只是鲍勃没有选择余地
Only Bob don't got a choice.
露丝  我实在搞不懂
I'm confused, Ruth.
我收留你们
I took you kids in,
把你和鲍勃当成自己的孩子
raised you and Bob like you were my own.
你们怎么能做出这种事情
How do you go and do a thing like this?
这不都是你教我们做的吗
We were just doing what you taught us to do.
你怀的是男孩还是女孩
Is that a boy or a girl?
你知道了吗
Do you know yet?
不知道
I don't know.
露丝  你准备怎么办
So, what do you want to do, Ruth?
我会等他
I'm gonna wait for him.
亲爱的露丝
Dear Ruth...
昨晚我又梦见你了
I dreamed about you again last night.
我对你可谓是
I guess I dream about you every night
日思夜想
and most days, too.
脑海中想到的都是你的面容
I hold your face in my mind.
耳朵里听见的全是你的声音
I put your voice together in my head.
我想象着你慢慢变长的秀发
I think about your hair getting longer.
和渐渐隆起的小腹
I think about your belly getting bigger.
监狱里有人为自己行为后悔
I hear people talk about regret,
不过我没有丝毫悔意
but I haven't got any.
持枪抢劫
我对自己做过的事情不会太过纠结
I don't think poorly on the things I've done.
与露丝·格思里一起被人称作"雌雄大盗"
被判25年徒刑
事情是我们做的
We did what we did,
我们就是这种人
and that is who we are.
你拿到信之前
They're gonna cross out this sentence
他们会删掉这句话的
before you get to read it,
但是我相信你知道其中含义
but I know you know what it says.
每天早上起来
Every day,
我就想是不是今天能够见到你
I wake up thinking today's the day I'm gonna see you,
那一天总会来临的
and one of these days, it will be so.
我会一直给你写信
And until then,
直到和你见面
I'll keep writing you.
每天都给你写
I'll write you every day.
有一天你拿到信的时候
And someday you'll get a letter from me,
抬头一瞥
and you will look up,
会发现送信的人正是我
and it'll be me who's handing it to you.
到那时无需文字传情
And then we can forget about words,
我可以抚摸你的脸颊
and I'll touch your face
可以亲吻你
and I'll kiss you.
鲍勃·马尔登  你醒着吗
Bob Muldoon, are you awake?
醒着
Yeah.
你有女儿了
You got a baby girl.
我会将女儿拥入怀中
And I'll take our baby girl in my arms.
然后我们离开
And we will ride off to somewhere...
远走高飞
somewhere far away.
有空回信给我
Write to me soon, any chance you get.
爱你的鲍勃
Love, Bob.
妈妈  妈妈
Mommy. Mommy.
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
-你睡得好吗  -很好
- How'd you sleep? - Good.
-你饿吗  -不饿
- You hungry? - No.
怎么了  过来
What's up? Come here.
我们一起再睡会儿
Let's go back to sleep.
妈妈  看我找到什么了
Mommy! Look what I found!
-你找到什么了  -小猫咪
- What'd you find? - Kitties!
-它们从哪里来的  -不知道
- Where did these come from? - I don't know.
你们几位啊
How many are you?
你们还很小呢
You're just a tiny little thing.
是不是啊小家伙
Aren't you tiny?
你们的妈妈呢
Where's your mama at?
你叫唤什么呢
What are you crying for? Huh?
-也许它想我抱  -什么
- Maybe he wants me. - What?
-也许它想我抱  -可能
- Maybe he wants me. - Maybe he does.
但你还有两口没吃完呢
But you still have two more bites.
小马驹跑啊跑
"And the little horse ran and ran
狐狸追了上来
and foxes chased him,
他能听见狐狸的叫喊声
and he could hear them barking.
还有狼群在追他
And the wolves ran after him,
他能听见狼在嚎叫
and he could hear them howling."
但他知道他们抓不到他的
"But he knew they couldn't catch him."
-熊  -是啊  一只小熊
- Bear. - Yeah, there's that baby bear.
你爸爸可喜欢熊了
Your daddy loves bears.
他过去常和熊一起摔跤
He used to wrestle with them.
把它们扑倒在地
He'd tackle them down.
给熊的鼻子上来上一拳
He'd bop them on the nose.
塞尔维  把鞋子穿上
Sylvie, put your shoes on.
好的
Okay.
-你好  -早上好  格思里小姐
- Hey. - Morning, Miss Guthrie.
我想你上班前找到你
I was hoping to catch you before work.
-出了什么事  -我能进门说吗
- Is something wrong? - I was hoping for a word.
-你一共有几只猫  -四只
- How many cats you got? - Four.
四只  这只叫什么名字
Four? What's this one's name?
薇洛
Willow.
它比较适合叫吉米
He looks like a Jimmy to me.
这些猫哪里来的
How'd you get those cats?
下来
Get down.
在后院捡到的
Found them out back.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
猫妈妈估计早就走了
Mama was long gone, I guess.
你需要别人帮你养几只吗
Well, you need someone to take a few of them off your hands?
几只猫我还是养得起的
I can handle some kittens, at least.
话说...
Like I said, uh...
他们准备让你去警察局走一趟
They're setting to get ready to call you down to the station,
不久就会有铺天盖地的新闻了
and, uh, it's gonna be all over the news later.
我觉得这事还是由朋友告诉你比较好
Thought best if you hear this from a friend.
什么事
Hear what?
鲍勃已经5次越狱未遂了
Bob tried to escape five times already.
这事儿你知道吗
Did you know that?
不知道
No, sir.
我还是跟你说吧
Well, maybe six times is the charm.
和他一起越狱的人
The boys he broke free with got caught
美国俄克拉何马州东北部城市
在巴特尔斯维尔想爬火车北上
trying to hop a train up near Bartlesville,
结果被抓住了
heading north.
鲍勃可能也是这么干的
Maybe Bob's doing likewise.
也可能他早已跑远了
Maybe he's already long gone.
可能吧
Maybe.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我不知道
I don't know.
有人打听过他吗
Anybody asking about him anybody at all?
没有
Nope.
他信里没提吗
What about those letters?
信寄出前你们不是就读过了
Everyone read them before they even got sent.
信里没说什么
They don't say anything.
你能把信带来吗
You want to just bring them in anyway?
我悉听尊便
I'll do whatever you want,
但是他不会回来的
but he won't come back.
他是不会像你们想的那样为了我回来的
He's not coming back for me if that's what you're thinking.
露丝
Ruth!
她那有线索吗
Did she tell you anything?
她告诉你什么了吗
没有  吉恩  她什么都没说
No, Gene. She didn't say a damn thing.
真意外  我觉得她对你会比较说得开
I'm surprised. I thought she'd like you better than me.
格思里被捕
这事儿就交给我吧
Let me have this one, huh?
当然啦  是你挨了枪子
Well, hell, pat. You're the one he shot.
当然由你来抓那混蛋
I'm gonna let you catch the son of a bitch.
露丝·格思里无罪释放
对不起我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
她今天受罚了
She had to have a time-out.
她和迈尔斯打架了
She got in a fight with Miles.
你为什么和男孩子打架
Why did you get into a fight with those boys?
他们骂我
Because they called me names.
光凭这个理由可不行
You need to have a better reason than that.
来吧  没事啦
Come on. Upsy-Daisy. Oy.
-晚上好  -你好
- Good evening. - Hi.
-小姑娘你好啊  -你好
- Hey, little girl. - Hi.
你今天真漂亮
Don't you look pretty today?
你是不是马上过生日了
You got a birthday coming up, don't you?
想要什么生日礼物啊
Well, you got your birthday list put together yet?
你可以考虑考虑
You better get on that.
让你妈妈帮你一起想
Get your mama to help you.
我听新闻里说了
I heard the news.
你想谈谈吗
Anything you want to talk about?
所有人都想从我这里找到线索
Everyone thinks I got something to tell them.
其实我真的无可奉告
I don't have a goddamn thing.
听他们说已经追踪他到蒙大拿州了
They say they traced him to Montana.
你觉得他在那里
You think he's in Montana?
我大可以打几个电话通通关系
I can make some phone calls
看看能否把这事了结了
see what I can do about putting an end to all this.
我自己就能了结这一切
I could put an end to all this right now all by myself.
我只需要
All I'd have to do is...
说出真相就可以
tell the truth.
你好你好小蓝鸦  为我来歌唱
Hey, little blue Jay, sing me a song?
歌唱那圣安娜  在圣安东尼奥
About Santa Ana at the San Anton'
你好你好小蓝鸦  让我偷偷亲一下
Hey, blue Jay, can I steal a kiss?
就像偷走榴弹炮  在冈萨雷斯一样
Like they tried to steal a Cannon from Gonzales?
蓝鸟蓝鸟  吹着口哨
Bluebird, whistle Waterloo?
我为你撑起荫凉
Will you come to the bower
你要不要来享
I've shaded for you?
你好你好小蓝鸦  为我来歌唱
Hey, little blue Jay, sing me a tune
回到六月的墨西哥  在那小路上
Down way in Mexico, back in June
女士  劳驾
Excuse me, ma'am.
女士
Ma'am?
沿着路继续开
Keep driving and stick to the highway.
-我们在哪里  -什么
- Where are we, anyway? - What?
我们在哪里  在哪个州
Where are we? What state are we in?
-密苏里州  -密苏里吗
- Missouri. - Oh, Missouri?
我知道你是谁了
I recognize you.
怎么开大声点
Hey, how do you turn it up?
在旁边  有一个...
On the side, there's a little, uh...
就是它
Yeah, that's it.
寂寞的夜
And lonely nights,
我思念你
I think of people that I miss.
每一天  我都在想你思念谁
And every day, I think of others you might miss.
你打算去哪里
Where you planning on going?
去个没人去过的地方
A direction that hasn't been invented yet.
我不知道
I don't know.
我对你无法忘怀
I could never forget about you.
无论欢乐与悲伤
The good times and the bad.
那么
So...
你是怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
-做什么  越狱吗  -是啊
- Do what... get out? - Yeah.
现在流行这个发型吗
Is this how fellas are wearing their hair?
老兄  我是这么走出来的
Well, man, I just started walking,
就和我之前说的一样
you know... just like I said I would.
就这么走出来的
And just walked out?
是的
Yep.
怎么走出来的
How's that work?
狱警们明天晚上都会来巡夜
Well, you know, the guards they come by your cell every night.
喊着"熄灯"
Sort of saying, "Lights out".
用警棍敲着栏杆
And rattling bars with their sticks.
有这么个狱警
And this one guard
喜欢开玩笑  和我们玩得开
he used to always joke and carry on with us.
有天晚上我对他说
And one night I said,
我们没几面可以见了
"Well, I won't be seeing you much longer.
我想我会在十天内出狱
I figure I'll be out of here in about 10 days."
他问  你怎么出狱
He said, "How you gonna do it?"
我说  就这么走出去啊
I said, "I'm gonna just walk right out the door."
他说他们会阻止我的
And he said they'd stop me.
然后我说  不行啊长官
And I said, "No, sir."
我有更重要的事要做
I've got better things to do.
他说  那也不行
And he said, "Well, that's not how it works."
我说
And I said, "Well,
有志者事竟成
it only works that way 'cause you think it has to.
上天在召唤我
See, I've got a higher calling.
我有老婆孩子
I've got a wife and a little girl
孩子需要爸爸
who needs her daddy."
然后他问我
And he asked me
怎么解释上天的召唤
what I know about higher callings...
如果我出去
says even if I do get out,
我应该就我的所作所为
I'm gonna have to answer to God
向上帝和恶魔做出解释
and the devil for the things I done.
我告诉他  该死
I tell him... Shoot.
我告诉他
I tell him...
我说  长官
I tell him, "Sir..."
过去的我是恶魔  现在我是个凡人
I used to be the devil. Now I'm just a man."
随着日子一天天过去
As the days tick by...
10天  9天  8天...
10, 9, 8...
到了最后一天
and on the last day,
监狱门开了
the bars open up,
我就这么走出来了
and I walk right out.
新闻里说你是跳车逃走的
News says you jumped off a work truck.
是的
Yeah.
好吧
Well...
你有吃的吗
Man, have you got anything to eat?
我还有点饿
I'm still a little bit hungry.
我给你找找
Well, I'll find something.
你最近见过露丝吗
Have you seen Ruth lately?
没有  好久不见了
Nope. It's been a while.
她现在不和她妈一起住了
She don't live with her mama no more.
有了个新房子
Got a new house.
新房子
A new house?
斯克里特一直照顾她
Skerritt's been looking after her.
替她打理一切
He got her all set up.
或许我应该告诉你
Guess I should tell you
我前几天接到个电话打听你
got a call the other day asking about you.
是吗  你怎么说的
Oh, yeah? What'd you tell 'em?
我说我没见过你  实话实说嘛
I told them I hadn't seen you, which I hadn't.
没想到那么快就见到你了
Didn't think I'd be seeing you so soon.
说真的
That's the truth.
这些钱
I guess that's about...
够还我欠你的债了
that's about what I owe you.
这钱哪里来的
Where'd this come from?
哪都有
All over.
谁的钱
Whose is it?
我的
It's mine.
听上去好像是木头软化了
Sounds like that wood's gone soft.
是啊  应该是
Yeah, I expect you're right.
再多钉子也架不住
More nails just won't hold it.
每次下雨
The whole gutter just comes off the house
排水槽都会掉下来
every time it rains like this.
我就爬上去重新钉好
You know, I go out there and nail it back up.
谁知道  转眼又掉下来了
Next thing you know, it's back off.
有功夫钉排水槽
Well, you can either do that
你还不如多准备些水桶接水
or get more buckets.
是啊  好主意
Yeah, I could do that.
能解燃眉之急
That'd be easier in the short-term, for sure.
那样的话
Then I'd have to haul that water out
每次下雨我都得往外倒水
every time it rains. I don't know.
-你好  -你好啊
- Howdy! - Howdy to you.
这场雨让我想起
Yeah, all this rain we've been having reminds me of
我们那次行军
that one march, it was.
每天只能前进十英尺
We'd get ten and a half inches in a day.
老兄
Man.
我那台中型坦克基本没油了
Oh, my middle tank out there has gone dry,
另两台也...
and the other two...
问下这是哪个镇啊
Say, can you tell me just what town we're in, exactly?
默里迪恩[密西西比东部城市]
This is Meridian.
这样啊
Okay.
我们刚从玫瑰谷[位于德州]过来
See, we passed through Glen Rose,
但没看到什么路牌
but we didn't see a sign...
也不知道走过了没有
didn't know if we'd gone to far, not far enough.
那得看你们去哪了
Well, that depends on where you're headed.
我们就来这
We're headed here.
你们要去猎鹿吗
You, uh, plan to hunt some deer?
正打算着呢
Thinking about it.
那天下着暴雨
Anyway, it rained so much,
坦克都被淹了
it filled up them tanks,
转天我老婆去检查它们
and my wife walked up there to check 'em the next day,
里面还有条鲶鱼
and there was catfish lyin' there.
坦克里全是雨水  还往外淌着
That thing filled up, and it was spillin',
鱼顺着水跑了出来
and it had come out in the spill.
-这是真的吗  -你说什么
- Are these real? - Come again?
这枪是真的吗
Are these real?
货真价实
You bet.
哪年产的
How old are they?
那把手枪得有125年的历史了
Well, that pistol goes back 125 years.
你瞎掰的吧
You don't say.
看到旁边那张小纸条了吗
See that scrap of paper there next to it?
那是一张名单
That there is a list...
写着所有死在
of every poor son of a bitch
这把枪口下的人名
who met his end at the barrel of it.
听起来真是忽悠
Sounds like a bunch of bullshit to me.
也许吧
Yeah, probably is.
你们想买点什么
Can I help you gentlemen find something in particular?
就随便转转
Nah. Just looking around.
有新消息吗
Is there any news?
今天没有
No, not today.
也许你需要这些
Figured you want these back.
上面都是灰尘
They're just gathering dust.
-你读过吗  -没有  夫人
- You read 'em? - No, ma'am.
为什么  谁都想看
Why not? Everyone else has.
我不应该看
They're not mine to read.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
当然
Mm, sure.
你说鲍勃
Do you mean what you said about
不会回来找你  是吗
Bob not coming back for you?
是的
Yeah, I did.
你是不是想等这件事平息了
Well, I was thinking maybe you all'd want to
就搬离这里
get out of town until all this blows over.
你是说等他被抓到之后吗
You mean till he gets caught?
我们还能去哪
Where would we go?
安全的地方
Someplace safe.
你也来吗
Would you come?
会有人和你一起
Someone would come with you.
我会一直住在这里吧
I think I'll just stay here. You know,
我得工作
I got to work,
赛尔维也要过生日了
and Sylvie's got her birthday.
我们会好好生活
We'll be just fine.
是呀  她快四岁了
Yeah, sure. She's gonna be 4.
-对吧  -是的
- Is that right? - Yep.
她想要什么礼物呢
Yeah. What's she want?
-她想要匹马  -真的马吗
- She wants a horse. - Like, a real horse?
-是的  -好吧
- Yep. - Yeah?
你把马养在哪呢
Where you gonna put it?
我倒认识个人
You know what? I know a man who...
可以从他那买一只  价格还算公道
who could sell you one for... for not a bad price.
-真的吗  -真的
- You do? - I do.
可惜我养不了马
I can't take care of no horse.
养不了马  也许
Well... No horse. Maybe I could,
我能给她送点别的礼物
maybe I could bring her something.
怎么讲
Why?
我最近在整理家
Well, I was just doing some cleaning, and...
收拾出来一堆小玩意
I... I may have a few deals just floating around that maybe,
也许里面有她喜欢的
uh... maybe she'd take to, you know? Just...
-小玩意  -嗯  就是些小东西
- A few deals, huh? - A few deals.
亲爱的露丝
Dear Ruth...
我不知道这封信该如何开头
I don't know how to start this letter.
我有万千思绪
I have got a million things on my mind,
需要释放
and I need to get them out.
你应该知道我越狱了
I know you know I am out,
希望你知道我要去找你了
and I hope you know I am coming for you,
正如我一直所说的那样
just like I always said.
正如我答应你的那样
Just like I always said I was going to do,
我要去找你
I am coming for you.
我多希望能在你的身旁
I wish I were standing at your side,
与你耳鬓厮磨  但现实并非如此
whispering in your ear, but that's not so.
我光着脚
I came across the woods and mountains
穿过树林翻过高山
with no shoes on.
长途跋涉  现在已经很近了
I traveled high and far, and now I am close.
近在咫尺
I'm so close to you.
近到几乎可以碰触到你的脸颊
I can almost reach out and touch your cheek.
给你  唐
Here you go, Don.
你们放松下吧
You boys take it easy, now.
你说你啊  鲍勃
Well... Look at you, Bob.
越了狱就往这儿跑
Break out of parson and head straight back here.
这可不太明智吧
Maybe not the smartest move.
只要你不告发我
Long as you don't turn me in.
迈尔斯呢
Where's Miles?
迈尔斯走了
Miles is gone.
-走了  -格拉迪斯也走了
- Gone? - Gladys is gone, too.
-现在就剩我了  -那谁管展览
- It's just me now. - Well, who's running the show?
没有展览了
No show to run... not anymore.
这不是弗雷迪的吗
Didn't this belong to Freddy?
我也不知道
Doubt it.
我还记得一起玩这个
I remember playing with this.
还有其他许多印第安小人
And all those little Indians...
其他的小人你放哪里了
have you got those Indians someplace?
弗雷迪的那些老古董都找不见了
Anything of Freddy's is long gone.
鲍勃  你想要什么
What do you want, Bob?
你没听说吗
I was just wondering if you'd heard anything.
听说什么
About what?
这地方有个家伙越狱了
About that local man who escaped from the penitentiary.
前几天吉恩·丹得勒和他几个手下
Gene Dentler and a bunch of his deputies
来找我聊了聊
come over a few days ago for a chat.
我告诉他们至少有六个家伙
I told them I could think of at least six sons of bitches
想看你死翘翘
who've got a mind to see you dead.
相比之下  还是坐下来赌一把
But that it'd be more fun to
看谁最先抓到你  应该更有意思
sit back and take bets on who gets you first.
那时你真是把身边的朋友得罪光了
You fucked over your share of people in your day.
是啊  所以我才被抓住
Yeah, and then I got caught.
但不是被他们抓住的
Not by them, you didn't.
他们还是别找我了
Well, they might as well quit looking.
老鲍就要消失了
Old Bob Muldoon's about to disappear.
那准备消失到哪去呢
And where's old Bob Muldoon gonna disappear to?
我想要安顿下来
I'm thinking about settling down,
建个小房子  开个店铺
build a little house, open a shop.
我不知道
I don't know.
慢慢变老  像你一样
Get old. Like you.
自己一人吗
On your own?
听说你给了露丝一套房子
Oh. So, I heard you bought Ruth a house.
我把一间老房让给她住
I'm letting her stay in one of my old places.
带一个大院子
It's got a big old yard
足够她女儿玩的
where her little girl can play.
那也是我的女儿
Hey, that's my little girl, too.
老兄  我告诉你
Man, I'll tell you...
她现在太可爱  你拿她真没办法
she's about cute enough to make you want to give up.
我承认  你这样做得对
You did one thing right. I'll give you that.
我尽全力去照顾她们两个
I do what I can to look after both of them.
是啊
Yeah.
接下来轮到我好好照顾她们了
Well, I guess I'll handle it from here.
-你这么想吗  -是的
- Oh, you think so? - Yes, sir.
我告诉你
Well, I'll tell you what.
你爱干什么干什么
You do whatever you want.
带上你的钱
You take all your money,
走得越远越好
and you get yourself as far away from here as you possibly can.
但你听好了
But you listen to me when I tell you...
离她们远点
You leave those girls alone.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你可以的
Yeah, you can.
那为什么我要离开
And why would I?
仔细想想  鲍勃
Well, now, think about it, Bob.
你会给她们带来多少麻烦
If you got any trouble coming your way...
她们肯定不想找麻烦
They sure as hell don't need that.
什么麻烦
What trouble is that?
你已经出狱了
You got out.
你还想得到什么
What more do you want?
我想要我的家人
I want my family.
我也是  但我已经没有家人了
So do I. But I don't got it.
我们这么办
Now, this is how it works.
我不会比现在伤你更多了
I will never hurt you more than I'm hurting you now.
我不会再对你动手
I will never lay another hand to you
不会扎你的手指  或是拧你的脸蛋
or prick your finger or pinch your cheek.
我不会报警
I won't call the sheriff,
也不会告诉他们你在哪
and I won't tell them where you've been.
但只要让我知道
But if I hear that old Bob Muldoon
老鲍还联系露丝
has been talking to Ruth Guthrie...
你就是自找麻烦
You asked me about trouble.
我保证麻烦会找到你头上
I will make sure you got some.
那天是弗雷迪先开的枪
Freddy was the one who shot first that day.
如果他没这样做
Nobody would have gotten hurt
谁都不会受到伤害
if he hadn't done that.
走吧  鲍勃
Go on, Bob.
我去开门了
I got to unlock my door.
趁没人看到你  快走
Get out of here before someone sees you.
找个安全的地方吧
Find yourself someplace safe.
钥匙在哪
Where are the keys?
-在车子里  -钥匙
- In the truck. - The keys?
我会给她带来麻烦吗
I'm gonna give her trouble?
就他能给她买房子吗
He thinks he can buy her a house?
-不是  -我才不管他那套
- No, sir. - I don't think that's how it works.
露丝会像逃离火灾一样  逃离那间房子
Ruth will walk away from that house like it was on fire.
笔  给我来支笔
Pen... I need a pen.
给我笔
Give me a pen.
该死
No damn sense.
亲爱的露丝
不好意思
Excuse me.
亲爱的露丝  我不知道如何开头
我在离你很近的地方  我们该走了
...抚摸你的脸颊...我们明晚见  日出就出发
我们养活自己...去我爸的农场...
你我还有赛尔维一起...我们该走了
过来
Come here.
我计划
I was thinking...
我们可以来个旅行
Maybe we could go on a trip...
等你过完生日
After your birthday.
你觉得怎样
What do you think about that...
去个新地方
going someplace new?
坐在车里  一直往前开
Just get in the car and drive and drive.
很有意思
Be real fun.
别跑
Hey, hold on.
让我看看
Let me see that.
给我
Give it here.
走吧
There you go.
快走
Come on. Go.
我把店关了
What do you think about me closin' up...
带你去兜一圈怎么样
take you for a ride somewhere..
逃离一下
Get away for a little bit?
伙计  最近好吗
Hey, sweetie. How you been?
还好
Just fine.
-我犯法了还是怎么着  -没有
- Break the law or something? - No.
感觉好久没见到你了
I just hadn't seen you around in years, it feels like.
我一直在这
I stay put.
-要来一杯吗  -不了  谢谢
- You want something to drink? - No, sir. Thank you.
我们在找你的一个老朋友
We're looking for an old friend of yours.
-你肯定听到消息了  -是的
- I'm sure you heard the news. - Yeah. Yeah.
几天前就有从门罗来的警察问过我
A couple cops came by from Monroe's asking questions.
好  你见过他吗
All right. Have you seen him?
当然没有
Sure haven't.
好吧
Look, all right.
你介意我到处看看吗
You mind if I take a look around?
比利  看下吧台
Billy, mind the bar?
要检查就快点
Hope we can make this quick.
别打扰到我的顾客
Don't want to rile up my customers.
从去年冬天就再没他的音信了
Haven't heard from him since last winter.
他给我寄过一封信
He sent me a letter.
-你回信了吗  -没有
- You write him back? - Nope.
你是不和鲍勃·马尔登
Weren't you part of his old gang...
露丝·格思里  弗雷迪一伙的吗
Bob Muldoon, Ruth Guthrie, Freddy?
不了  早不干了
Nope. Got out of that racket.
我开了这家酒吧
Got myself this business.
该死  我把钥匙忘楼下了
Hell. Left the darn key downstairs.
等我一下
Well... Hold up.
我要快点回前台  不能离开太久
I'm gonna need to get back to the register before too long.
我当书签用的
Been using it as a bookmark.
这下我不知道看到哪页了
I guess I lost my place.
露丝给你的吗
Ruth give it to you?
她寄来的
She mailed it.
想让我寄给鲍勃
Asked me, uh... asked me to send it on to Bob.
你没有寄
You never did.
我说过  我不太会寄信
Like I said, I'm bad with correspondence.
多久的事了
How long ago?
小姑娘几岁了来着
How old's the little girl?
三岁  快四岁了
3, going on 4.
那就这么长时间了
About that long, then.
好吧
Okay.
-这个我带走可以吗  -随你
- Uh, mind if I hang on to this? - By all means.
如果有消息就给我们打电话
I'm sure you'll call us if you hear anything.
当然
Sure bet.
看
Look at this.
这是你穿的第一件衣服
This is the first thing you ever wore,
在你出生那天
the day you were born.
你那时好小
You were so tiny.
看看多小啊
Look how small it is.
我抱着你回家  你睡了好久好久
I brought you home, and you slept and slept for hours.
你真是个好女孩
You were such a good little girl.
我们把它带上
I'll bring this with us just because...
也许我们有天会用到它
We might need it someday.
小马捡起它的鞋子
"And the little horse picked up his shoes
一口气跑出黑暗的树林
and ran until he was out of the dark woods.
他跑到小鱼的河中
He came to the river where the fish had been.
小鱼已经离开了
The fish was gone now, and
没有人能阻止他过河
there was no one there to stop him from crossing.
他穿越河流  翻越山脉
He crossed the river and climbed the hill,
没多久  就回到了家
and before too long, he could see home."
宝贝  怎么了  你好安静
What's wrong, sweet girl? Why are you so quiet?
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be fine.
只需静候  好吗
You just wait and see, okay?
亲爱的鲍勃
你有鲍勃的消息吗
Have you heard from Bob?
-为什么不进来坐下  -不了
- Why don't you come in? - No.
我知道鲍勃就在附近
I know Bob's been around.
你把这个给他好吗
Will you see to it that he gets this?
这是什么
What is it?
你想看就看吧  反正你都会去看的
You can read it if you want. I figure you will anyway.
如果你见到他  能告诉他
If you see him... Can you tell him...
算了  给他就好了
Just... just give it to him.
亲爱的鲍勃
Dear Bob...
希望你永远收不到这封信
I hope you never get this.
我希望你走过那扇门
I want you to come through that door,
带我们离开  一如你所承诺
take us away just like you always said.
但你不能
But you can't.
你不能来这里  至少现在不行
You can't come here... not right now.
我也不能跟你走
And I can't go with you.
一旦你来  你就会被抓住
If you come here, they'll catch you.
如果我们一起走
If we go with you,
他们也会找到我们
they'll find us.
结局不该如此
It can't end like that.
我不允许有这种结局  无论对我们
I can't let it end like that, not for us...
还是对赛尔维
And not for Sylvie.
我不能让这种事发生
I can't let that happen.
所以  我们会离开
So, we're gonna go.
你来找我们时  我们已经不在了
If you come looking for us here, we'll be gone.
我们会去一个谁都不认识我们的地方
I'll go somewhere where no one knows who we are,
或者  我们可以耐心等待
or we can wait for the time
直到整个世界都将我们忘记
to be right and the world to forget about us.
我不知道如何表达
I don't know how to explain this any better,
但我知道你能理解我的意思
but I know you know what I'm talking about.
我们已经等了很久
We've waited so long.
只需再多等一阵子
We've just got to wait a little longer.
你就能来找我们了
Come find us.
我知道你会来的
I know you will.
希望你会  我们会重逢的
I hope you will. We'll find each other.
我深深爱着你
I love you so much. I do.
该起床了  宝贝
It's time to wake up, baby girl.
小甜豆
Sweet pea...
早上好
Good morning.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
你见过他吗
You seen him?
我们去过他女朋友家了
We stopped by his girl's place.
哈蒂根说如果见到你
Hartigan said to tell you something
告诉你件事
if we ran into you.
什么事
What's that?
该死  我忘了
Shit, I forgot.
还是我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
你拿着它该干嘛干嘛
You take that and do what you will.
如果没找到他
And if you don't find him,
也别回来
that don't give you cause to come back here.
明白吗
You understand?
别以为我不管这事了
Don't think I'm washing my hands off all this.
如果你们再敢踏进小镇一步
And if you set foot in this town again,
哪怕只是有牵扯她们的想法
if you even think about bringing those girls into this,
我都会杀了你们
I'll kill you.
就这样
And that'll be that.
老兄
Dude.
沃伦·米勒
Warren Miller.
谁编的这些名字
Who makes up the names?
不是编的  都是真人
They ain't made up. They're real folks.
都死了  但是...都是真的
I mean, they're dead, but... they're real.
真的吗
Oh, really?
听别人说的
So I'm told.
-露丝和赛尔维也是吗  -是的
- Ruth and Sylvie too? - Yes.
-不会再有人跟着我们吧  -不会了
- Nobody's gonna be asking after us? - Not anymore.
好样的
Good job.
许愿了吗  许的什么愿
You make a wish? What did you wish for?
不能告诉你
I'm not telling.
好吧  还有小秘密呢
All right. You keep your little secret, huh?
我看起来如何
How do I look?
和原来一样
You look like you.
那就好
Then that'll do.
看来我没有虚度光阴
The way I see it, I didn't waste my time.
-记得老乔吗  -记得
- You remember old Joe Cranston? - Yep.
记得他跟我去圣路易斯那次吗
Remember that time he and I went up to St. Louis?
在我们出发前
He spent about three hours getting prettied up
他早起了三个小时打扮
before we got in the car to go up there.
我说  乔  你干嘛呢
I said, "Joe, what are you doing?"
他说  万一我出了什么事
He said, "Well, in case anything happens to me,
我希望妈妈还能认出我来
I want to make sure my mama can recognize me."
他穿上那件他十二岁时就在穿的外套
So he put on this coat he had when he was 12 years old,
系扣子时  由于他个头太大
and he tried to button it up, and he was a big old boy,
外套从后背撕开了
and it ripped right out the back.
他就一直穿着那玩意儿
And he kept that thing on all the way
从圣路易斯再到德克萨斯
up to St. Louis and back down to Texas.
像个邋遢鬼
He looked like a damn raggedy Ann.
等回来时  我说
And when we got back, I said,
乔  即便你出事了
"Joe, you know your mama would have recognized you
你妈妈也能认出你的
if something happened to you."
他说  对啊  因为我穿了这件外套
He said, "Yeah, 'cause I had my coat on."
他没懂我意思
I mean, he didn't get it.
人们...
You see, people...
好多事都不懂  却自以为是
they don't know things the way that they think they know them.
赛尔维...她会认出我的
Sylvie... she's gonna know me.
她都不用看就能认出我
She'll know me without looking at me.
露丝...我在街上她就能感觉到
And Ruth... by God, she'll feel me coming down the street.
我们一直是...
I mean, we always just been...
另一个彼此
You know, just two parts of the same.
我们也会吵得不可开交
I mean, we would fight,
就像两个孩子抢一个皮球
and we'd fight like two kids with a ball.
她会发脾气  把家里搞得底朝天
And she'd rip through the house like she was on fire,
而我却只想抱住她
and I'd just want to hold her.
我只想抱住她
I'd just want to hold her.
她会大吵大闹  发疯失控
But she'd be yelling and flapping around so quick,
像只蜂鸟一样暴躁
it was like a hummingbird.
而我会说  露丝
I'd say, "Ruth
你就冲我吼吧  吼到嗓子哑了为止
you can scream at me till your voice is gone.
反正都一样
But it doesn't make much difference.
当你喊够了
Because when you're all done screaming,
我还是会陪你坐在房间里
it's just gonna be you and me sitting here in a room."
她说  是啊
And she said, "That's right.
我们永远都在一起
It's always just gonna be the two of us."
多漂亮啊  喜欢吗
Look how pretty that is. You like that?
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
还有最后一个惊喜了
Well, there's, uh, one last surprise, I suppose.
知道怎么打开吗
You know how to open this?
来打开吧
All right. Let's open her up. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我得到它时  也像你这么大
So, this was mine when I was about your size.
看看你拿着什么样
Let's see how it looks on you.
-替我向露丝问好  -我会转告的
- Say hi to Ruth for me? - I'll tell her.
或许不要再见比较好
I guess I hope I never see you again.
-小狗怎么叫  -汪汪
- How's a dog sound? - Ruff, ruff.
汪汪  试试看
Ruff, ruff? Try that.
汪汪  小猫呢
Ruff, ruff, and then go back to cat.
试试看
Try that.
有人翻山越岭
And some will travel 'cross the land,
只为找寻爱人
looking for their love
再来一次
One more time.
有人凝视大海  仰望天空
Others gaze upon the sea and search the sky above
可我不这样
But count me not among them
那已是过往
As I was before
因为我早已
Now I go wandering
不再流浪
Wandering no more
如主所见  我不再流浪
I shall go wandering no more, my lord
我不再流浪
I shall go wandering no more
因为你就是
You are all the treasure
我找寻多时的宝藏
That I've been searching for
我不会再流浪
I shall go wandering no more
为什么不练练呢
Why don't you hang on to this?
一周后我再来看你
Maybe in a week or so, I'll check back in with you,
那时说不定你就能给我弹歌了
and maybe you'll play me a song.
-怎么样  -不要
- How's that? - No.
-不要  -我明天要去旅行
- No? - I'm going on a trip tomorrow.
旅行  真的
A trip? Is that right?
她真棒
She's great.
你还好吧
You all right?
我很好啊
Yeah, I'm fine.
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
抱歉我没想打扰你的
Well, I didn't mean to wear out my welcome.
不  我只是问问
No. I just want to know.
我就是很愿意来
Just happy to be here.
你要离开吗
You're planning on leaving?
-是的  -好吧
- Yes, I am. - All right.
去哪里
You know where you're headed?
不知道  我只想离开这里
No, I don't know yet... just away from here.
-如果需要帮助  -我什么都不需要
- Well, if you need any help... - I don't need anything.
谢谢你的邀请
I appreciate the invitation,
祝你晚安
and I bid you good night.
晚安
Good night.
露丝
Ruth.
我想告诉你一件事
I want to tell you something.
这些话  我憋了很久了
This has been, uh, weighing on me for some time.
在医院时
Uh... When I was in the hospital,
我不是
I wasn't,
我不是在策划还是什么的
I wasn't sitting there making plans or anything.
我从没想过跟鲍勃对着干
You know, I got nothing against Bob.
而那天发生的事  那种风险本来就有
And what happened... I mean, that's the risk.
是我工作的一部分
That's... that's part of my job.
除此之外
And beyond that,
我没有因为他的为人
I don't hold it against him
或是所作所为  对他怀恨在心
to be who he was or do what he was doing,
现在也没有  我很高兴能活着
and I still don't. I'm glad to be alive.
很高兴认识你
I'm glad to know you.
如果你未曾经历那些过去
And if you weren't who you were
未曾和他海誓山盟
and had never been with him
而我们依然相逢于此
and somehow we had still come together right here, right now,
我的感觉也不会改变
I wouldn't feel any different.
明白吗
Do you understand?
你还记得那天吗
You remember that day?
我记得自己挨了一枪
I remember getting shot.
就好像肩膀被打了一拳
I remember feeling like I'm getting punched in the shoulder,
仰望着德州悠远的天空
seeing the big old Texas sky.
我都记得
I remember that,
-但是...  -你看见我了吗
- but, uh... - Did you see me?
没有
No, ma'am.
听见我后来说的话了吗
Did you hear what I said after?
我看了你的供词
I read your statement.
那不完全属实
It wasn't all true, you know.
我不是个昏头昏脑的小女生
I wasn't just a little girl who got dragged in over her head.
我知道我做了什么
I knew what I was doing.
我想...
Well... I think that,
许多所言并非事实
a lot of things were said that might not have been true.
但你就那样做了  他也是
But you did what you did. So did he.
无论你做过什么
And whatever it is you've done,
当我看见你和你女儿时
when I see you with your daughter
我眼中只有幸福
all I see is good.
或许我只是在耍你
Maybe I'm just fooling you.
是吗
Are you?
等等  等等  该死
Wait. Wait, God damn it!
该死
God damn it.
你冲我开枪
You shot me.
为什么
Why'd you shoot me?
-我没见过你  -是的  先生
- I've never even seen you. - No, sir.
那为什么  钱吗
What's this about... money?
你  就因为你
You... it's about you.
你和那个女孩儿
You and the girl.
你们想做的一切
Everything you tried to do.
你要开枪吗
You gonna shoot me?
我不想让你觉得我欠你什么
I don't want you to think I owe you anything.
你没有
No, you don't.
我惟一有所亏欠的人就是鲍勃
The only person I owe anything to is Bob.
不是的
That's not so.
这些事我一直压在心里
I've been storing things up all this time,
彻夜不眠
sitting awake at night,
反复想着要对他说的话
thinking of all the things I want to say to him.
现在发生那么多的事
Except now I have so many things,
我都不知道从何说起
I don't know how I'd ever start.
我只有赛尔维和我自己
All I had was Sylvie and I.
我都不知道怎么在信里写
I didn't know how to write about her.
换做你会怎么写
How do you write about something like that?
我记得她出生的那天
I remember the day she was born.
我吓坏了
I was so scared, and
我试图阻止她的到来  可她还是来了
I tried to keep her from coming, but she came anyway.
他们把她送到我怀里时
And when they put her in my arms,
我们彼此对视
we just stared at one another,
我就觉得  为这样的爱死掉也罢
and I thought I would die from all that love.
我想在信里跟他描述
And I tried to write to him about it
让他也能体会那种感觉  但是...
so he'd know what it was like, but...
我找不到合适的词语
but I just couldn't find the words to do it right.
所以我就不再...不再写信
So, I just stopped... stopped writing to him.
我想见面时再讲给他
I figured that I'd just tell him all at once when I saw him.
待他走进那道门
He'd walk through the door,
我就会知道如何讲述
and I'd know exactly what to say to him,
一切也会回归正轨
and things would be the way they used to be.
所以我留着每样小东西
That's why I've been saving every little thing.
四年了  我一直没睡好
And I haven't slept in four years.
我累了
And I'm tired.
我太累了
I'm just so goddamn tired.
那就歇歇
Then rest.
你会陪我等吗
Will you wait with me while I do?
你还好吧
Are you all right? Okay?
你要...你要干什么
Hey, what are you... what are you doing?
开车  快开车
Drive, man. Drive.
-钥匙归你  -加油
- Please, just take the keys. - Step on the gas, man!
加足油门
Step on the gas!
好吧
All right.
沿着公路走
And just stick to the highway.
走到6号公路时右转
When you get to highway 6, you turn right.
我...我只想见见我的家人
I... I'm just trying to go see my family,okay?
我不过是想回家
I'm just trying to get home.
我不想打架  都按你说的来
I ain't gonna put up a fight. I'll do whatever you want.
我只想回家见家人
I just want to make sure I get home to them.
我只想搭一下你的车
I just want you to drive.
你家什么样
What's your family?
什么
What?
你家都有谁
What family have you got?
有妻子孩子吗
You have a wife and kids?
没有
No.
我是去看望父母
No, I'm going to see my parents.
你父母
Your parents?
-你爸妈  -是的
- Mom and dad? - Yeah.
你叫什么
What's your name?
-威尔  -你叫威尔
- Will. - Will's your name?
是的
Yeah.
威尔  有喝的吗
Will, do you have anything to drink?
没有
No.
You don't?
该死
Shoot.
我该去找点儿水的
I could go for some water.
你要去...医院吗
You need to... you need to go to a hospital or something?
不要
No, man.
沿着公路开  在6号公路拐弯
Just stay on the highway. Turn at highway number 6.
好的
Yes, sir.
你应该看出来我中弹了
Well, I guess you can tell I got shot. Yep.
那些人来抓我
These men came looking for me.
想把我干掉
They wanted to put me under.
有人派他们  他们就来了
Somebody sent them, and they came from somewhere,
他们找到我了
and they got me.
抓住我了
They got me pretty good.
不过没弄死我
They didn't get me good enough.
看吧
See.
告诉你爸爸今天载了谁
Tell your daddy who you gave a ride to today.
好的
Okay.
谁
Who?
什么
What?
你是谁
Who are you?
放下枪
Drop it!
没事了
It's all right.
你记得
You remember...
你第一次为我做事吗
Remember the first run you ever did for me?
你和弗雷迪
Heh. You and Freddy.
第一次
The very first one.
我从没为您做过什么  先生
Nah, I never did nothing for you, sir.
你俩都觉得自己很厉害
You both thought you were so tough.
其实都是小孩子而已
You were little boys.
我想回家
I want to go home.
十分钟前我给摩根打了电话
I was on the line with Morgan 10 minutes ago,
告诉他发生了什么
told him how it happened.
不  不  不  你再打
No, no, no. You get 'em back on the phone
一直打到他们来
'till they come down here.
我不知道谁对谁干了什么
I don't know who did what to who.
查到身份了吗
Did you get an I.D. yet?
没有  但是...
No. I mean, yeah, but...
他不过是布鲁森附近的混混吧
he was just some son of a bitch up near Bruleson.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
斯凯里特死的太狼狈了
Skerritt went out like a sucker, huh?
我送露丝回家
I'm gonna take Ruth on home.
不用  我让泰迪去了
No, I got Teddy doing that.
还是我去吧
Yeah, I'm gonna take her.
等一下
Wait here.
没事的  没事  没事
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
我去叫救护车
I'm gonna call an ambulance.
我一直在等你
I've been waiting for you.
住手  很痒的
Stop it. That tickles.
对胎儿不是应该唱唱歌什么的吗
I thought that's what we're supposed to do... sing to 'em.
就说说话吧
Just talk.
那我来跟你讲
Well... Let me tell you about something.
我来跟你讲讲未来的样子
I'm gonna tell you about the future.
很久很久以后
In the future,
我很老很老
I'm a very old man.
我站在门口
And I'm standing in the door.
我们的房子门口
We're in a house.
那是我们的房子  离这儿很远
It's our house, somewhere far away from here,
绿草成茵  夕阳西下
where everything is green and the sun is almost set.
我们驻足
And where we're standing,
仿佛在招手
the way I see it, we're waving to somebody.
也许正是向你招手
And maybe that somebody is you,
你走了那么久  终于回来看我们了
come to see us after a long time gone.
若真是你
If it is you...
我们很高兴能与你相见
We are very happy to see you.
宝贝
Hey, sweetie.
再跟我讲讲那房子
Tell me more about that house.
我没在和你说话
I'm not talking to you.
很大很大  是个农场吧
It's big. Maybe a farm.
很古老  比我们还老
It's old. It's older than us.
我还觉得那好像是我建的
At the same time, though, I feel like maybe I built it.
不好说
There's no telling.
真不好说啊
There's just no telling.
他们非圣人